Guide to the United States Political Ephemera Collection, 1856-2000s RL.11320
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
United States political ephemera collection
1856-2000s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11320
5.0 Linear Feet
The United States Political Ephemera Collection contains campaign materials on both the national and state levels between the years 1856-2008. Materials are mostly related to the Democratic and Republican parties, but include materials from the American Labor party, Greenback party, League of Women Voters, Libertarian party, National Prohibitionist party, and Socialist party, as well as non-partisan materials. Materials include campaign pamphlets, flyers, form letters, newsletters, press releases, booklets, handouts, newspapers, posters, bumper stickers, and buttons.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The United States Political Ephemera Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts and transfers between 1950s-2000s.
Related Materials
The Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Presidential Campaign Ephemera contains materials from various United States presidential elections.
Collection Overview
The United States Political Ephemera Collection contains materials from assorted national and state-level campaigns and elections, except U.S. presidential campaigns. (Presidential campaign and election materials are held in the Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Presidential Campaign Ephemera.) This collection is divided into two series: National Politics and State Politics. National Politics contains materials related primarily to the Democratic and Republican parties and their campaigns for congressional and senate elections. It also includes materials from the American Labor party, Greenback party, League of Women Voters, Libertarian party, National Prohibitionist party, and Socialist party, as well as non-partisan materials. Also included are anti-war protest materials from the Vietnam Moratorium Committee. Materials include campaign pamphlets, flyers, form letters, booklets, handouts, newspapers, bumper stickers, and buttons. Filed alphabetically by political party.
State Politics includes campaign material from different states, each placed in their own subseries. The majority of the material comes from North Carolina statee and local elections, with many of the materials from Durham. Materials are mostly related to the Democratic and Republican parties, but also include the American Labor party, Socialist party, and non-partisan materials. Materials include campaign pamphlets, flyers, form letters, newsletters, press releases, booklets, handouts, newspapers, posters, bumper stickers, and buttons. Arranged alphabetically by state; within subseries arranged alphabetically by political party.
Elections -- North Carolina -- History -- 20th century; United States. Congress. Senate -- Elections; Politics -- North Carolina -- Durham; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements; Elections -- United States; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- History; Republican Party (U.S.) -- History; Socialist Party (U.S.) -- History
- National Politics, 1856-1996 and undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  National Politics contains materials related primarily to the National Democratic and Republican parties, but also includes materials from the American Labor party, Greenback party, League of Women Voters, Libertarian party, National Prohibitionist party, and Socialist party, as well as non-partisan materials. Also included are anti-war protest materials from the Vietnam Moratorium Committee. Materials include campaign pamphlets, flyers, form letters, booklets, issue papers, handouts, newspapers, bumper stickers, souvenir plastic bags, buttons, and a paper hat. Arranged alphabetically by political party.
  - AFL-CIO, 1968 (Box 1)
    Pamphlet, Newspaper
  - AFL-CIO Voter Registration Posters, 1960 (Box 3)
  - American Communist Workers Movement, undated (Box 1)
    Flyer
  - American Labor Party Platform, 1947 (Box 1)
    Pamphlet
  - Americans for Common Sense, 1981 (Box 1)
    Form letter
  - Anti-war Protest, 1968 and undated (Box 4)
    3 Campaign and protest buttons
  - Committee on Political Education, 1960 (Box 1)
    Pamphlets, campaign literature
  - Democratic Congressional Wives Forum, 1960 (Box 1)
    History of Democratic Women booklet
  - Democratic National Committee:Summary of Campaign Issues, 1930-1996; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Summary of campaign issues, press release, bumper sticker
  - Democratic National Convention, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    Press release
  - Democratic Party, 1856-1984; 7 folders (Box 1)
    Form letters, fundraising letters, clippings, campaign literature
  - Democratic Party, 1948 (Box 3)
    Newspapers, clippings
  - Democratic Party, undated (Box 4)
    Campaign buttons
  - Democratic Political Action Committee, 1948-1949; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Pamphlets
  - Greenback Party Platform, 1952 (Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian National Committee, 1984 (Box 1)
    Memo, accounting documents
  - Libertarian Party Convention, 1985 (Box 1)
    Memos, newsletters, statement of candidacy, accounting documents
  - Lincoln Day Speech Material, 1967 (Box 1)
    Booklet
  - Miscellaneous Newspapers, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
    National Democratic and Republican newspapers
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1971 (Box 3)
    Newspapers: New Solidarity, News of Greece, Spring Movement; Black and white poster/mask of Vietnam soldier
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1952 (Box 1)
    Form Letter
  - National Prohibitionist Party, 1948-51 (Box 1)
    literature, publications
  - National Unity Committee, John Anderson, 1982 (Box 1)
    Form letters
  - Nonpartisan Materials, 1974 and undated; 2 bags (Box 4)
  - Nonpartisan Democratic and Republican National Platforms, 1956-1960; 4 folders (Box 1)
    Democratic and Republican platforms, "Facts and Figures, Past and Present," booklets, newsletters, sample ballot
  - People for the American Way, 1982 (Box 1)
    Form letters by Norman Lear
  - People's Coaltion for Peace and Justice, 1971 (Box 1)
    Meeting agenda
  - Poor People's Campaign, 1968 (Box 4)
    Campaign button
  - Race Relations, 1954-56 (Box 1)
    Notes, handouts
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, Education Fund, 1984 (Box 1)
    Newsletter
  - Republican Campaign Materials, 1980 (Box 1)
    Souvenir plastic bags
  - College Republican National Committee, undated (Box 1)
    Issue papers
  - Republican Coordinating Committee, 1966-1968; 4 folders (Box 1)
    Brochures, memos, pamphlets, Task Force on the Conduct of Foreign Relations - Latin America - United States
  - The Republican Leadership of the Congress, 1966-68 (Box 1)
    Press releases
  - Republican National Committee, 1963-1965; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Pamphlets, newsletter, party recruitment literature
  - Republican National Convention Women's Division, undated (Box 1)
  - Republican National Convention, 1961-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Memos, pamphlet, Lincoln day, press releases, reports
  - National Republican Senatorial Committee, 1984 (Box 1)
    Senate journals, form letters
  - National Sustaining Program for Republican Party Headquarters, 1966-1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - The Republican News, 1948 (Box 1)
    Newspaper
  - Republican Party, 1952-1981 and undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
    Pamphlets, fundraising form letters, bumper sticker, sticker, campaign literature, convention keynote address
  - Republican Party, undated (Box 3)
    Republican party paper hat souvenir
  - Republican Party, 1998 and undated (Box 4)
    5 Campaign buttons
  - Republican Party Congressional elections, 1978 (Box 1)
    Form letter by Gerald Ford
  - Sheet Music "USA = USA: The Land of Liberty", 1975 (Box 1)
  - Socialist Party, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Socialist Party Congressional Program, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Socialist Party Convention Badges, 1948-1958 (Box 1)
  - Socialist Party Platform, 1917-1968; 6 folders (Box 1)
    Pamphlets, booklet
  - Socialist Worker's Party, 1972 (Box 1)
    Campaign literature, pamphlets
  - United States Senatorial Business Advisory Board, 1980 (Box 1)
    Form letter, pamphlet
  - Vietnam Moratorium Committee, undated (Box 1)
    Flyer, pamphlet
- State Politics, 1908-2008 and undated; 2
  State Politics includes campaign material from sixteen different states, each placed in their own subseries. Materials include campaigns for U.S. House of Representatives and Senate, state legislature, governor, mayor, city commissioner, judge, and civic bond issues. The majority of the material comes from North Carolina state-wide and local elections; North Carolina local election materials are primarily from Durham. Materials are mostly related to the Democratic and Republican parties, but also include the American Labor party, Citizens Party, Socialist party, and non-partisan materials.
  Materials include campaign pamphlets, flyers, form letters, newsletters, press releases, booklets, handouts, newspapers, posters, postcards, bumper stickers, stickers, and buttons. Arranged alphabetically by state. Within subseries arranged alphabetically by political party.
  - California, 1972; 1
    - Republican Party Campaign, 1972 (Box 1)
      Congressman John G. Schmitz, form letter
  - Connecticut, undated; 2
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, undated (Box 4)
      Campaign button for Abraham Ribicoff
  - Florida, 1984; 3
    - Democratic Congressional Campaign, 1984 (Box 1)
      Claude Pepper, form letter
  - Georgia, 1950; 4
    - Liberty Party Gubernatorial Campaign, 1950 (Box 1)
      Jessie W. Jenkins, form letter
  - Illinois, 1914-1942; 5
    - Democratic Campaigns, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Socialist Party Chicago Platform, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Indiana, 1944; 6
    - Republican: Carl H. Mote, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Kansas, 1942-1962; 7
    - Democrat Congressional Campaign, 1942 (Box 1)
      Herbert L. Drake, Flyers
    - Republican Congressional Campaign, 1962 (Box 1)
      Bob Dole, Pamphlet
  - Louisiana, 1952; 8
    - Non-partisan Voting Information, 1952 (Box 1)
      Pamphlet, ballot
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Maryland, 1938-1976; 9
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1938-1976 (Box 4)
      Campaign buttons for Paul Sarbanes, Joseph Tydings, and Millard Tydings
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1976 (Box 1)
      Pamphlets, car decoration
    - Democratic Senatorial Campaign, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1970 (Box 4)
      Campiagn lapel for Glenn Beall Jr.
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Massachusetts, 1981; 10
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Minnesota, 1934-1984; 11
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1984 (Box 1)
      Fundraising form letter
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1934 (Box 1)
  - New York, 1908-1964; 12
    - American Labor Party, 1946 (Box 1)
    - American Labor Party Primary Campaign Committee, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Democratic Mayoral Campaign, 1948 (Box 1)
      Robert F. Wagner, Jr., pamphlet
    - Democratic Party, 1946 (Box 1)
      State platform
    - Democratic Senatorial Campaign, 1964 (Box 1)
      Robert Kennedy, pamphlet
    - Socialist Party, 1908 (Box 1)
      Letter of Socialist candidate for governor
    - Socialist Party Candidates, 1935 (Box 1)
      Buffalo, NY; pamphlet
    - Socialist Labor Party, 1949 (Box 1)
  - North Carolina, 1940-2008 and undated; 13
    - Citizens Party, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1952-2008 and undated; 23 folders (Box 2)
      Flyers, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, newspapers, handbooks, form letters, postcards, handouts, meeting minutes, bumper stickers
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1964-1984 (Box 3)
      Newspapers
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1950-1996 and undated (Box 4)
      12 Campaign buttons, lapels, match boxees, nail file. Campaigns include Ralph Campbell, Nick Galifianakis, Harvey Gantt, Luter Hodges, Jim Hunt, Frank Montgomery, Dan K. Moore, Richardson Preyer, Terry Sanford, Robert Scott, Willis Smith, and William B. Umstead
    - Democratic Congressional Campaigns, 1973-1985; 3 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for Ike Andrews and Tim Valentine; Pamphlets, newsletter, form letter.
    - Democratic Gubernatorial Campaigns, 1940-1996; 16 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for J.M. Broughton, Rufus Edmisten, Charles Johnson, Jim Hunt, Beverly Lake, Ralph W. McDonald, Dan Moore, Terry Sanford, W. Kerr Scott, and William Umstead; Pamphlets, newspaper clippings, press releases, campaign literature, bumper stickers, decal, correspondence
    - Democratic Party, 1960-1977; 2 folders (Box 2)
      Lakewood precinct, Durham; meeting minutes, member badge, press releases
    - Democratic Senatorial Campaigns, 1950-1996; 2 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for Willis Smith and Harvey Gantt; postcard, sticker
    - Durham County Returns, 1980 (Box 2)
      Newspaper clipping
    - Durham Voters' Alliance, 1976-1984 (Box 2)
      Newsletters
    - Fifteenth Annual Candidates Meeting, Durham, 1962 (Box 2)
      Durham; candidate information
    - Miscellaneous Materials, 1960-1984 (Box 3)
      Non-partisan: Durham precinct map, The North Carolina Independent newspaper,; Durham Committee on Negro Affairs election poster
    - National Abortion Rights Action League, 1984 (Box 2)
      North Carolina newsletter
    - Non-partisan Election Information, 1968-2008; 4 folders (Box 2)
      Candidate information, newspaper, pamphlets; includes Durham Civic Bond Issue, and 2008 North Carolina ballot
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1960-2008 and undated; 16 folders (Box 2)
      Flyers, pamphlets, form letters, handouts, bumper stickers, newsletters, greeting cards
    - Republican Campaign Materials, 1952-1984 (Box 3, Oversize-folder 1)
      Newspapers; poster for C. Allen Foster, candidate for NC attorney general in 1980.
    - Republican Congressional Campaigns, 1960-1966; 3 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for Jim Gardner, Walter Green, and Holland L. Robb; flyers, pamphlet, bumper stickers
    - Republican Gubernatorial Campaigns, 1960-1984; 8 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for Bob Gavin, Jim Martin, Richardson Preyer, and Charles W. Strong; bumper stickers
    - Republican Party, 1964 (Box 2)
      Bumper sticker: Register Republican
    - Republican Secretary of State Campaign, 1984 (Box 2)
      Campaign for Pat Dorsey; bumper sticker
    - Republican Senatorial Campaigns, 1948-1956; 2 folders (Box 2)
      Campaigns for Joel A. Johnson and John Wilkinson; correspondence, campaign literature, pamphlet
    - Some Profiles in an Age of Challenge, undated (Box 2)
      Asa T. Spaulding, N.C. Mutual Life, Durham
    - Unidentified political party, 1996 (Box 2)
      Bumper Sticker: Harlow N.C. House
  - South Carolina, 1974; 14
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Wisconsin, 1952-1962; 15
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1952 (Box 2)
      Newsletters, press release, form letter
    - Democratic Campaign Materials, 1952 (Box 3)
      Newspaper clippings
    - Socialist Party State Platform, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Wyoming, 1964; 16
    - Democratic Senatorial Campaign, 1964 (Box 2)
      Historians for Senator Gale McGee, form letter